准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
蟹堡塔
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
技术总监
动画总监
制片指导
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
所以我本来是准备好要炸薯条的
So, I was all ready to drain the fries
可是我把薯条炸得有点太久了
but I cooked the fries slightly too long
于是
So
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
于是薯条有了奇怪扭曲的形状
So here's where the bizarre twist comes in
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
根本就没有炸过头
They weren't overcooked at all
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你看
Look
蟹堡王怎么了
What happened to the Krusty Krab?
早安
Good morning
蟹堡塔现在正式开门营业
The Krusty Towers is now open for business
盛大开业
蟹堡塔
为什么要盖酒店啊  蟹老板
Why did you build a hotel, Mr. Krabs?
问得正好  小伙子
I'm glad you asked, son
记不记得我先前去参加快餐大会
Remember when I went to that fast food convention
酒店
住进了家豪华酒店
and stayed in that fancy hotel?
我住的房间可漂亮了
I had a beautiful room
员工特别的友好
The employees were so friendly
他们无微不至地关照我
They catered to me every whim
就算我要求很丢脸也照办
no matter how demeaning it was
因为他们的生活有一条规矩
because they lived by a code
而它正镌刻在壮丽火炉之上的黄金中
And that code was engraved in fine gold
above the grand fireplace
我们绝不拒绝客人的请求
连最荒唐的都一样
一切都很完美
Everything was perfect
拿到账单就不完美了
Until I got the bill
收银员
账单
他们不管什么都收我钱
They charged me for everything
共计
汉堡一个还二十五块
$25.00 for a hamburger
客房
泳池
桑拿
汉堡
要是连个垃圾汉堡都能收那么多钱
If they could charge that much for a lousy burger
就想想我能靠垃圾蟹黄堡收多少钱吧
imagine how much
I could charge for a lousy Krabby Patty
于是  蟹堡塔诞生了
And thus, the Krusty Towers was born
裤头村怎么会有人住酒店
Why would anyone stay at a hotel in Bikini Bottom?
这里虽然风景好  但是很偏僻啊
It's in the middle of scenic nowhere
在这就只能被水母蛰
There's nothing to do but get stung by jellyfish
看吧
See?
进来
Come inside
漂不漂亮啊
Isn't it beautiful?
新来的酒店员工在哪里
Where are all the new hotel employees?
第一个来酒店的客人
Me first hotel guest
看我把他引进来
Watch me reel him in
欢迎光临蟹堡塔
Welcome to the Krusty Towers
我们的格言是
where our motto is
我们绝不拒绝客人的请求
"We shall never deny a guest
连最荒唐的都一样
even the most ridiculous request"
真不错
That's great
我要来份双层蟹黄堡
I'd like a double Krabby Patty
不加洋葱  多加腌椰菜
with no onions and extra pickles
如果你要蟹黄堡的话
If you want a Krabby Patty
就得租间房间还有订购客房服务
you have to rent a room, and order room service
我午餐只能吃一个小时
I've only got an hour for lunch
你啊  引流引得可真是专业
Boy, you reeled that one in like a pro
那好  章鱼哥
Okay, Squidward
你来做前台
you run the front desk
我要来份蟹黄堡
I'd like a Krabby Patty, please
这里现在是家酒店了
This is a hotel now
如果你要蟹黄堡的话
If you want a Krabby Patty
就得租间房间还有订购客房服务
you'll have to get a room, and order room service
好
Okay
一份蟹黄堡跟一间房间
One Krabby Patty and one room
要加奶酪
With cheese
蟹黄堡上也可以加奶酪吗
And can I get cheese on the Krabby Patty, too?
派大星  你家离这才四百码远
Patrick, you only live 400 yards away
干嘛要来住酒店
Why do you want to check into a hotel?
有时候我就只是想要远离坐世
Sometimes I just need to get away from it all
这酒店什么都有啊
This hotel has everything
快给我
Give me that
签登记簿
Now sign the register
我都不知道还有考试
I didn't know there would be a test
我没念好书啊
I didn't study
派大星  你只要签好名就行了
Patrick, all you have to do is write your name
那就好
Okay
能不能别看
Do you mind?
不准看
Don't look
好了
Done
差不多就行
Close enough
房门钥匙给你
Here's your room key
我要帮手来帮忙提包
I'll need some help with my bags
你哪来的包
How can you have bags?
你刚才才知道这里是酒店
You just found out this is a hotel
原来这里是酒店吗
This is a hotel?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
来了  章鱼哥
Yes, Squidward
把派大星跟他包带到他房间去
Take Patrick and his bags to his room
那我蟹黄堡呢
What about my Krabby Patty?
给人家拿蟹黄堡去
And bring him a Krabby Patty
章鱼哥  你把派大星的包提到他房间
Squidward, you can take Patrick's bags up to his room
海绵宝宝  你去做蟹黄堡
SpongeBob, you go make the Krabby Patty
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
咋回事
What's the matter?
一点点体力活就怕了吗
Afraid of a little manual labor?
我是章鱼哥  我得干活谋生
"I'm Squidward, and I have to work for a living"
那好
Fine
我们走  派大星
Let's go, Patrick
这部电梯只能客人用
This elevator is for guests only
你用员工电梯去
Take the employee elevator
员工电梯
你包里什么东西
What's in these bags?
石头吗
Rocks?
还真是石头
These are rocks
你包里怎么全是石头
Why is your suitcase full of rocks?
我又没教你怎么过日子
I don't tell you how to live your life
好了  你房间到了
Well, here's your room
入住愉快
Enjoy your stay
章鱼哥  等等
Squidward, wait
继续好好干
Keep up the good work
那个啥我还会再给的
and there will be more where that came from
你的蟹黄堡  先生
Your Krabby Patty, sir
章鱼哥  石头挺酷
Hey, Squidward, cool rock
等会  海绵宝宝
Hold on a second, SpongeBob
给你  我的大善人
Here you are, my good man
谢了  派大星
Thank you, Patrick
那个啥我会再给不少的  我的好朋友
There's plenty more where that came from, my good friend
章鱼哥
Squidward
又咋了
What now?
我不喜欢我蟹黄堡上的皮
I don't like crusts on my sandwich
那个是面包
It's a bun
本来就全都是皮
It's all crust
我要怎么把面包上的皮给弄掉
How am I supposed to cut the crust off a bun?
削掉
Peel it
满意了吧
Happy?
客房服务
Room service
你点的五十份蟹黄堡来了
Here's the 50 Krabby Patties you ordered
你可不可以再给我做件事情
Could you do one more thing for me?
要不你叫海绵宝宝做吧
Why don't you ask SpongeBob?
好办法啊  章鱼哥
Good idea, Squidward
我能为你效劳吗  先生
How may I serve you, sir?
我要你来跟我一起吃掉这些蟹黄堡
I need you to eat these Krabby Patties with me
好的先生
Yes, sir
等会
Hold on
章鱼哥
Squidward
派大星要你帮忙
Patrick needs your help
什么
What?
他怎么不提前问我
Why didn't he ask me
我都好不容易一路走下楼了
before I walked all the way downstairs?
他本来说他不想打扰到你的
He said he didn't want to bother you
然而他又忘了这回事
But he got over it
万岁
Hooray
谢了  章鱼哥
Thanks, Squidward
蟹老板  这简直荒唐得不得了
Mr. Krabs, this is ridiculous
派大星的要求完完全全不合理
Patrick's being completely unreasonable
他爱怎么不合理就可以怎么不合理
He can be as unreasonable as he wants
看牌匾  章鱼哥
The plaque, Squidward
看牌匾
The plaque
可是蟹老板
But Mr. Krabs
绝不拒绝客人的请求
Deny no guest
喂  派大星
Well, hello, Patrick
你要章鱼哥马上过来吗
You need Squidward to come up right away?
会马上到的
He'll be right there
泡泡澡吗
A bubble bath?
我凭什么要给你洗泡泡澡
Why would I give you a bubble bath?
因为蟹老板说你会给我洗
Well, because Mr. Krabs said you would
一定要把我的后背擦得特别光亮
Be sure to make my back extra shiny clean
就这样了
That's it
我受够了
I've had enough
章鱼哥等等
Squidward, wait
马桶又堵着了
The toilet's backed up again
你不能坐那部电梯
You can't take that elevator
你可是员工
You're an employee
再也不当了
Not anymore
我辞职
I quit
辞职
Quit?
你不能辞职啊
You can't quit
欢迎光临蟹堡塔
Welcome to the Krusty Towers
章鱼哥
Squidward?
请来一间房  要顶楼的
One room, please, on the top floor
你以为你在干什么
What do you think you're doing?
我要度假
I need a vacation
我劳累过度了
I'm overworked
何况蟹堡塔最适合放松了
And what better place to relax than Krusty Towers
这里绝不拒绝客人的请求
where we shall never deny a guest
连最荒唐的都一样
even the most ridiculous request
我没必要把房间租给你
I don't have to rent you a room
我有现金
I got cash
房门钥匙给你
Here's your room key
海绵宝宝  把我东西提到我房间里去
SpongeBob, carry my things to my room
遵命  客人先生
Aye, aye, guest sir
你可以把我抱到我房间里去
And you can carry me to my room
我凭什么要那么干
And why in tarnation would I do that?
你长着好端端的四条腿
You've got four legs that aren't broken
看牌匾
The plaque
我们绝不拒绝客人的请求
连最荒唐的都一样
17层
真可惜坐不了电梯
Too bad we couldn't take the elevator
可是电梯只让客人坐
but it is for guests only
而且你就只是一员工
and you are an employee
你的房间  先生
Your room, sir
我想订购客房服务了
And I'd like to order room service
我要来份蟹黄堡
I'd like a Krabby Patty
要加奶酪  脚趾甲
with cheese, toenail clippings
还有鼻毛
and nose hairs
你肯定是在开玩笑
You've got to be kidding me
我要它五秒钟就送来
And I want it here in five seconds
好的先生
Yes, sir
给你  先生
Here you are, sir
行  你的恶心三明治买到了
Well, you got your stinky sandwich
自己吃了吧
Now eat it
我可不吃这东西
I'm not going to eat this
你来吃
You are
什么
What?
要是以为我会吃  你就是痴心妄想
You're out of your mind if you think I'm going to eat that
那个蟹黄堡其实并没有完全
That's not really a Krabby Patty
加了奶酪  脚趾甲跟鼻毛
with cheese, toenails and nose hair
明白你意思了  小子
Now I get you, boy
好了  章鱼哥
All right, Squidward
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
对不起  蟹老板
Sorry, Mr. Krabs
奶酪都用光了
We were all out of cheese
万岁
Hooray
什么事  章鱼哥
What is it, Squidward?
送一打饼干过来
Send up a dozen cookies
要有从前我妈做的那味
just like mother used to make
手工饼干来了
Here's your homemade cookies
完全没有我妈从前做的那味
These don't taste anything like mom used to make
那你妈是怎么做的饼干
Well, how did your mother make 'em?
我怎么知道
How should I know?
问我妈去
Ask my mother
章鱼夫人
邮件
你们好
Hello
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
没有用  蟹老板
No good, Mr. Krabs
让我来  孩子
Allow me, boys
太棒了
Great
既然我待洗衣物放进了后备厢
Now that me laundry is in the trunk
你完全就能坐前边的地方
There's room for you to sit up front
我们去烤饼干吧  孩子们
Let's go bake some cookies, boys
万岁
Hooray
怎样
Well?
真是厉害
I'm impressed
还真有我妈以前做的那味
These are just like mother used to make
希望我妈厨艺能更好点
I just wish mom was a better cook
所以你满意了吧
So you're all taken care of
就一个小小的问题
Just one teensy, tiny problem
这房间太丑了
This room is hideous
去重新设计
Redesign it
海神十四世的风格倒不错
Neptune the 14th would be nice
什么
What?
我们绝不拒绝客人的请求
"We shall never deny a guest
连最荒唐的都一样
even the most ridiculous request"
完美
Perfect
这房间就跟原先的一模一样啊这
This room is exactly the same as when we started
重回基础最好不过
Nothing like getting back to the basics
我们出去吧  海绵宝宝
Let's get out of here, SpongeBob
你们临走前
Before you leave
我要去游个泳
I want to go swimming
泳池在外头
The pool is out back
疯了吧你
Are you crazy?
我才不去外头游泳
I'm not going outside to swim
快下来
Come on in
水很舒服的
The water's fine
还有什么又傻又不合理的要求吗
Anything else stupid and unreasonable that you want?
差不多了
Nope, that's it
不要我帮你嚼食物了吗
You don't need me to chew your food for you
还是不要拿我脊椎给你做抓背器了吗
or make you a back scratcher out of my own spine?
是不是还不要扑灭太阳
Or maybe extinguish the sun
让你眼睛不被光照到是吧
so the light don't get in your eyes?
不必  我很满意
No, I'm good
我也是
Me, too
还有室内游泳池
An indoor pool
这地方可真是高档
This place is fancy
炮弹来了
Cannonball
医院
盖酒店打一开始就是个馊主意
That hotel was a bad idea from the start
原来那是酒店吗
That was a hotel?
你的账单  先生
Your bill, sir
要一万五
$15,000?
床
绷带
药物
病房服务
共计
你该不会要心脏病发作了吧
You're not going to have a heart attack, are you?
怎么会有这么贵
Not at these prices
酒店不干了
Forget hotels
医院的架子才是放钱的好她方
This hospital racket is where the money is
原来这是家医院吗
This is a hospital?
收拾行李  小伙子们
Pack your bags, boys
你们要去上医学院了
You're going to medical school
万岁
Hooray
老天爷啊
Oh, boy
泡芙老师
失业了
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
技术总监
动画总监
制片指导
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
泡芙老师
滑浪学校
早安  泡芙女士
Good morning, Mrs. Puff
我是费兹先生
I'm Mr. Fitz
是驾校教练评审机构的代表
I represent
the Voting Teachers Accreditation Bureau
你也清楚的
As you know
你的教练证即将到期  需要更新
your teaching certificate is up for renewal
但是我们注意到这一班里
However, we've noticed there have been
有异常多的不及格案例出现
an unusually large amount
of failings from this classroom
不可能啊
That's impossible
我这么多年的教学生涯里
In all my years of teaching
教过的班级只有一个学生不及格
only one student has failed my class
是没错  可是他有1258056次不及格
Yes, but he's failed 1,258,056 times
你不懂的
You don't understand
海绵宝宝他
SpongeBob is
朽木不可雕
unteachable
不能因为教练不力而去责备学生
We cannot blame the students
for the incompetence of the teacher
我准备好开船了
I'm ready to drive
准备好迎接我的驾考了吗  泡芙老师
Are you ready for my driving test today, Mrs. Puff?
泡芙女士  如果海绵宝宝这次又挂
Okay, Mrs. Puff, if SpongeBob fails this test
就必须换掉你
you will be replaced
海绵宝宝  来给费兹先生示范一下
Okay, SpongeBob, let's demonstrate for Mr. Fitz
我在滑浪学校里教你的知识
everything I've taught you in boating school
开船前要做的第一件事是什么
Now, what's the first thing we do before we start boating?
系好安全带
Seatbelt-a-rooni
马上就行
One second
然后要做什么呢
Then what do you do?
发动引擎
Start the engine?
对
Yes
现在要怎么办
What do I do now?
开船
Drive the boat
我这回及格了吗  泡芙老师
Did I pass this time, Mrs. Puff?
没有  海绵宝宝
No, SpongeBob
你不及格
You failed
我不及格
I failed?
挂的并不是你  海绵宝宝
It is not you that's failed, SpongeBob
挂的是泡芙老师才对
It's Mrs. Puff that's failed you
你的教练职务被免除了
You are relieved of your teaching duties
我不用再教海绵宝宝了吗
I won't be teaching SpongeBob anymore?
不教
No more
海绵宝宝了
SpongeBob?
我还以为不会有这么一天
I thought this day would never come
再见了  海绵宝宝
Good-bye, SpongeBob
一路走好吧你
Have a nice life
终于自由了
Free at last
滑浪学校
我害泡芙老师失业了
I got Mrs. Puff fired
你们好  不中用的同学们
Hello, worthless students
泡芙老师
我是你们的新教练
I'm your new instructor
我课上挂科的就没有一个
No one's ever failed my class
活下来的
that's lived through it
我可以向你们保证  接下来这四周
I can assure you, these next four weeks
会是你们痛苦人生中最悲惨的时光
will be the worst years of your miserable lives
你们的脊椎会断掉
Your spines will break
你们的牙齿会疼死
Your teeth will ache
你们的眼睛会充满血丝
Your eyes will be bloodshot
你们最后不是毕业风光开船
You will drive out of this school in style
就是挂科坐着奶奶的篮子被推出去
or you will be carted out in your granny's handbasket
每个人都要遵守好班规
Everyone will follow the rules of the class
第一条班规  严禁讲话
First rule: no talking
是不是说
Does that mean
第二条班规  班上严禁吃东西
Second rule: no eating in my class
有谁想要吃夹心糖
Would anyone care for a bon-bon?
夹心糖
我要来颗
I'll eat one
爱挑哪个挑哪个
Pick your favorite
好不好吃
How's it taste?
味道可不错了
It's a delightful taste sensation
班上严禁吃东西
No eating in my classroom
如果有人有勇气待在这班上的话
Now, if anyone else is man enough to stay in this class
这么说你很有勇气了是吧
Looks like you're the man
这位海绵
Sponge
有吗
I am?
你是不是要来学开船的
Do you want to learn how to drive or what?
是  长官
Yes, sir
我准备好去开船了
I'm ready to drive
你这是在干什么
What do you think you're doing?
准备过驾考  长官
Ready for my test, sir
你还不算准备好开船
You're not ready to drive yet--
必须要先学会那个
until you learn that first
这是有史以来最累人的驾驶训练道路
This is the most grueling driving course ever devised
你要掌握每个转弯突起跟裂缝的位置
You will learn every turn, bump and crack on it
但要先从爬开始学
You'll start out crawling it
爬
Crawl?
一二一二
Hup two, hup two
左转
Left turn
裂缝
Crack
突起
Bump
半毛钱
Nickel
有半毛钱
Hey, a nickel
注意看路  学员
Keep your eyes on the road, cadet
石块
Pebble
我真是为你感到羞耻  学员
I'm ashamed of you, cadet
居然能被一个小小的石块绊倒
Tripped up by a wee pebble
你在我班上是要学什么
What are you supposed to be learning in my class?
是开船  长官
How to drive, sir?
正确
Affirmative
但在你学会开船之前
But before you learn to drive
你必须要学会爬
you must learn to crawl
然后学会走
And then you learn to walk
然后学会跑
and then you learn to run
但在你学会走之前  必须先学会爬
But before you learn to walk, you must learn to crawl
现在给我爬
I want you to crawl
遵命  长官
Sir, yes, sir
现在上路
Now, get out there
停
每个好司机都得里里外外摸清他的船
Every good boater
needs to know his vehicle inside and out
给
Here
去拆了那艘船
Go take that boat apart
真是不错  小子
I'm impressed, son
再装回去
Put it back together again
还挺简单
That'll be easy
确定吗
Are you sure?
确定啊
Yeah
把这东西放到那玩意上去然后
You just put the jing-a-mahoos on the poo-hickey and, uh
可能要那么几分钟
I might need a couple of minutes
好了  长官
It's ready, Sarge
我的水母啊
Jumping jellyfish
终点线
注意行人
Watch for pedestrians
检查后视镜
Check mirrors
看好限速
Observe that speed limit
注意行人
Watch for pedestrians
所以
So, um
我做得怎样
how'd I do?
你做得怎样
How'd you do?
怎么不去问这行人的碎尸
Why don't you ask
the shattered remains of this pedestrian
你怎么办到的
how you did?
我对这道路的前后边角都了如指掌了
Now I know this course forward, backward and sideways
我可以去开船了吗
Am I ready to get behind the wheel?
还没到那程度
Not quite
戴眼罩来做
Now do it blindfolded
几天后
1,003
1,004
1,005
143号石块
Pebble number 143
你是不会再绊到我的了  143号石块
You will not trip me up again, pebble number 143
1,006
1,007
1,008
拿了个火腿三明治的老太婆
Old lady with a ham sandwich
1,009
1,010
1,011
1,012
one th
恭喜你了
Congratulations
你可以准备好去开船了
You're ready to get behind the wheel
真的吗
Really?
我准备好了
I'm ready
我
I'm
来查验你学习成果了  小子
Let's see what I taught you, laddie
遵命长官
Yes, sir
在143号石块处左转
Left turn at pebble number 143
拿球的小孩
Kid with a ball
好孩子
Nice boy
开得好
Nice driving
到前边去侧方停车
Now parallel park up ahead
非常好
Very good
现在  小子
Now, boy
给费兹先生查验成果的时刻已经来到
the time has come to show Mr. Fitz what you learned
遵命长官
Yes, sir
第一步  安全带
Step one: seat belts
做的好  学员
Excellent work, cadet
下一步是什么
What's next?
第二步是  发动引擎
Step two would be: ignite engine
第三步
Step three
第三步是
Step three would be
戴眼罩
engage blindfold
什么
What?
戴眼罩不可以开船
You can't drive a boat with a blindfold on
那样子犯法
That's illegal
可我不戴眼罩开不了
But I can't do it without a blindfold
开啊  小子
Drive, boy
快开啊你
Drive
汽油
易燃
危险
求救
Mayday
你已驶离道路
You're off course
我内心可舒坦了
I feel so serene
终于可以远离那杀人狂魔海绵宝宝了
now that I'm away from that homicidal maniac, SpongeBob
刹车  小子
The brake, son
遵命长官
Aye, aye, sir
弄好了  长官
Here you go, sir--
我拧掉两颗螺栓就拆下来了
all I had to do was unscrew two little bolts
我要逼停这东西
I'm going to stop this thing
帮我跟老婆说我爱她
Tell my wife I love her
放马过来
Come get some
危险
Man down
抱歉
sorry
不好意思
Excuse me
抱歉
Sorry
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
抱歉派大星  我没法抽空陪你聊天
Sorry, Patrick, I can't stop to talk right now
我看不到东西了
I can't see
我的裤子
My pants
我看不到东西了
I can't see
我及格了吗
Did I pass?
要是驾考有毁灭城市这个模块
Well, if there was a "destroy the city" part of the test
你早及格了
you would have
某些人可真是神经质
The nerve of some people
抱歉  海绵宝宝
Sorry, SpongeBob
你又挂科了
you failed again
连我们最好的教练都不能教好你
Even our finest instructor could not teach you
泡芙女士  你又被录用了
Mrs. Puff, you're hired again
泡芙老师
Hey, Mrs. Puff
真抱歉我朽木不可雕
Sorry I'm "unteachable"
没事
It's okay
优等
费兹先生把我教练证拿回来了
Mr. Fitz gave me my teaching certificate back
并且你的档案也被炸没了
And your dossier was destroyed in the explosion
所以你差不多从来没不及格过
So it's as if you never failed
我有个回归礼物要送你  泡芙老师
I got you a "welcome back" gift, Mrs. Puff
我把所有碎片找出来粘回去了
I found all the pieces and glued them back together
泡芙老师
我保证我绝不会再来考个一百万次了
I promise it won't take me a million tries thistime